Guide to the Mahmoud Hammad Collection AD.MC.091
al Mawrid Arab Art Archive, NYU Abu Dhabi
- Series VI: Photographic Materials
  - VI.A. Photographic Prints, cuid280
    Series includes photographs of the artist and family; photographs of Hammad with students and colleagues at the Faculty of Fine Arts; photographs from travel, including many from the Accademia di Belle Arti in Rome (with fellow Syrian students such as Adham Ismail, Mamdouh Kashlan, and Ismail Husni, and Jordanian artist Mohanna Durra and Palestinian artist Ismail Shammout; and photographs of artworks by Hammad.
  - VI.B. Photographic Slides, cuid281
    This series includes images of artwork by Hammad, including images from the inauguration of the Martyr's Monument he designed for Najha Cemetery outside Damascus; artwork by others, including exhibition shots from ​​Foundation Vasarely Aix-en-Provence; source images of historical events and figures.
- Series VII: Other Items in the Possession of the Artist, cuid282
  Series includes postcards collected by the artist, likely as source material for art or as reference for lectures and other writing.